<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aghora Guru</title>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <description>A website with blog posts ,pages and portfolio</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 02:20:06 +0000</pubDate>
    
      <item>
        <title>MandelBrot Set With Excel</title>
        <link>/2023/02/02/MandleBrot_Set.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2023/02/02/MandleBrot_Set.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Making MandelBrot-Set with Excel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/MandelBrot/MandelBrotBanner.webp&quot; alt=&quot;drawing&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, that is click-bait … This is what I thought when my professor said you will be making Mandelbrot set in Excel !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But considering the computing power of my laptop and Excel, I was convinced. Ps: I did it on my friend’s laptop as Linux doesn’t have any good Excel alternative ( fact 1 - I use Manjaro as my daily Driver ( except for gaming duh ) while writing this blog)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were able to pull off this Mandelbrot in excel using 10 Iterations and going more than this makes your system awestruck .. it freezes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was the load on the CPU when I tried to load the Excel file. (fact 2 The file size is ~60 MB)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/MandelBrot/SysLoad.avif&quot; alt=&quot;img&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/MandelBrot/Excelview1.avif&quot; alt=&quot;excelview1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are not some machine codes(not with decimals of course) it is the computation that happens based on the formula which we give in the table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When all the computations are working well, you will get this as the result!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/MandelBrot/mandelbrot.avif&quot; alt=&quot;drawing&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not bad for an Excel Computation. Though we cannot zoom into it and get a mind-gaze experience like this, this still is good for me at least.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-computation&quot;&gt;The Computation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Mandelbrot set is a mathematical set of points that are defined using a complex number system. The math behind it involves iterating a complex function, which is defined as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

\[f(z) = z^2 + c\]

&lt;p&gt;Where $z$ is a complex number and $c$ is a constant. The function is iterated over and over again, with the result of the previous iteration being used as the input for the next iteration. The iteration stops when the absolute value of the result is greater than 2, or when the iteration count reaches a maximum value. The number of iterations it takes for the absolute value to exceed 2 is the number of times the point is in the Mandelbrot set.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, the Mandelbrot set is the set of all complex numbers “c” for which the sequence of numbers f(0), f(f(0)), f(f(f(0))), etc. remains bounded in magnitude. This means that the magnitude of the numbers in the sequence never grows larger than a certain value (which is usually set to 2).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Mandelbrot set can be visualized by plotting the complex number “c” on a complex plane and coloring the points according to whether or not the corresponding sequence remains bounded. This produces a beautiful and intricate pattern, which has been studied extensively by mathematicians.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;iterating-manually-using-excel&quot;&gt;Iterating manually using Excel&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took numbers from -2 to +2 with a step size of 0.01 for rows and columns&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/MandelBrot/excelcol.avif&quot; alt=&quot;drawing&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/MandelBrot/excelrow.avif&quot; alt=&quot;drawing&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then we use the data table from excel to fill up those rows and columns which get formed by the above 2 images.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;    We use the cells B1 and C1 in the Data Analysis tool
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/MandelBrot/excelrow2.avif&quot; alt=&quot;drawing&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;    It would look like this in the first iteration.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/MandelBrot/excel2.avif&quot; alt=&quot;drawing&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;    Use this formula for
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-js&quot; data-lang=&quot;js&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;IMSUM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;IMPRODUCT&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;B3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;B3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;),&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;B3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;    The second iteration will look like this
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/MandelBrot/excelrowsmall.avif&quot; alt=&quot;drawing&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now make a new sheet and put this formula at A1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-js&quot; data-lang=&quot;js&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;IMABS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;Sheet8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;B3615&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And reduce the height and width of cells to make the Mandelbrot visible! It will be without colors, you can change the style of the sheet. Just select all the cells and make a sheet color format and set if the cell value &amp;lt; 2 color it with black.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/MandelBrot/excelverysmall.avif&quot; alt=&quot;drawing&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When everything goes well , the final sheet after zooming out should look like :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/MandelBrot/mandelbrot.avif&quot; alt=&quot;drawing&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s it ! You made fractal using Excel !&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My system</title>
        <link>/2023/01/16/My-System.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2023/01/16/My-System.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;journey-of-os-hoping&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journey of OS Hoping&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/MySys/osgif.gif&quot; alt=&quot;drawing&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like all teenagers, I was using Windows for Gaming (mostly) and some coding (school-level stuff). When Covid happened, during lockdown started reading about the latest tech news. And I was amazed to see how Linux is growing. And I was like “I should try it”. And I did. And I was amazed. Amazed by the customization, performance, community, software, security, privacy, and stability(which I broke many times). I was amazed by the speed and looks. I was amazed by everything. I was using it as a VM and I joined my undergrad. My friend asked me to dual-boot it. Started with Zorin. Was using it for college purposes. Wasn’t into customization at that time. Had all my workspaces set up [a mini actual developer feeling :)]. After a while, my friend again asked me to use Kubuntu, a KDE-based distro. I was like “why not”. He said you can do a lot of customization, I was like YESS I’m in! At first, it felt a little weird without the Zorin Vibe. And Guess what I customized it in such a way that it felt like Zorin (with extra additions). This was the time when I started liking the bar which exists on almost all distros.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This new attraction of the bar made me customize the bar so much that all the necessary controls are in the bar which I was able to access easily. KDE gave so many widgets that allow people to have some stuff that you need to manually code which will take lots of trials and run!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After using KDE for quite a long time ~ 7 months, one fine day when I did a system update, the package databases weren’t syncing. I was not able to install anything new. The widgets stopped working and I was pissed off. Then again my friend asked me to use Manjaro, an arch-based distro with GDM. At first, I was like, meh it looks like normal Ubuntu I don’t like it. And I was too attached to KDE that I wanted that workflow as badly as possible. And he sent me the Gnome customizations. And again I fell for it. Lots of Reddit forums and youtube videos. I started experimenting with it. Now the workflow I have is such that with the keybindings only I can move around the system (unless you see configs).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The current shell theme is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnome-look.org/p/1619506&quot;&gt;Otis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Legacy Applications theme is &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/EliverLara/Kripton&quot;&gt;Kripton&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The icon theme is &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/PapirusDevelopmentTeam/papirus-icon-theme&quot;&gt;Papirus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using Gnome-extensions for the top bar and the dock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The terminal is Gnome-terminal with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/romkatv/powerlevel10k&quot;&gt;zsh&lt;/a&gt;. Using blur-my-shell extension to get transparent background and blur it .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/MySys/neofetch.png&quot; alt=&quot;drawing&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And as my course is focused on AI ML installed the GPU related stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/MySys/nvidia-smi.png&quot; alt=&quot;drawing&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My Github repo&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.github.com/aghoraguru&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; where mostly college stuff and coding happens 😊.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;My friend&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; repo &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.github.com/SuperSecureHuman&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s a wrap ! I would strongly suggest whoever reads this to start using Linux (but don’t just OS hop too much ) , try out different stuff , break - fix - repeat .
I have always wanted to make Linux Personal, so learning to do all these customization . Soon will be moving to Arch and will update this when some good stuff happens . 😊&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/MySys/bye.gif&quot; alt=&quot;drawing&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
